Let me ask you a question. What did you do yesterday?
دعني أسألك سؤالاً. ماذا فعلت بالأمس؟
Did you go to the beach? Take a walk around the block?
هل ذهبت إلى الشاطئ؟ هل تمشيت قليلاً في الحي؟
Cook yourself some sweet and sour chicken because it's amazing?
هل طهوت لنفسك بعض الدجاج الحلو والحامض، لأنه رائع؟
What about the day before yesterday?
ماذا عن أول أمس؟
How about two weeks ago?
ماذا عن منذ اسبوعين؟
When I was young, my parents wanted me to keep
عندما كنت صغيرًا، أراد والديّ أن أحتفظ
a daily journal so that I could look back on it
بيومية لكي أستطيع أن أعود إليها مستقبلاً
sometime in the future and remember places I'd gone and experiences I'd encountered.
وأتذكر الأماكن التي زرتها والخبرات التي اكتسبتها.
Unfortunately, I wrote in it about once a year,
لسوء الحظ، كنت أكتب بها مرة في السنة،
which is terrible because the entries weren't
وكان سيئًا لأن كل ما كتبته لم يكن مُفصلاً
detailed at all and just touched on high-level events.
على الإطلاق ويحتوي فقط على الأحداث المهمة.
A good journal entry should have a date so you know when it occurred,
يجب أن تحتوي المُدخلات الجيدة في اليومية على تاريخ لتعرف متى حدثت،
a heading so you can give it a short description of that entry,
وعنوان لتتمكن من كتابة وصف قصير لها،
and then the entry itself that has all of the information.
ثم بعد ذلك المُدخلات نفسها التي تحتوي على جميع المعلومات.
Each time a new entry is made in the journal,
في كل مرة تقوم بمُدخل جديد في اليومية،
it's like making a commit in the repository.
كأنك تقوم بإيداع في مستودع.
And just like your journal entries,
ومثل مُدخلاتك في اليومية تمامًا،
you want your commits to be frequent and
تريد للإيداعات أن تكون متتالية و
descriptive so you can see the progress of your project over time.
تحتوي على وصف لكي يمكنك متابعة تقدمك في المشروع بمرور الوقت.
Git automatically records the date and
يقوم Git أليًا بتسجيل التاريخ و
the content changes that have been made when a commit is created,
تغييرات المحتوى التي حدثت عند إنشاء الإيداع،
so all you need to do is provide the descriptive heading or message for the commit.
لذا، كل ما تحتاج لفعله هو أن تضع عنوانًا وصفيًا أو رسالة تصف الإيداع.
You want journal commits to be frequent so that you can
تريد أن تكون الإيداعات في اليومية متتالية لترى
see the ups and downs in life over time.
النجاحات والإخفاقات في الحياة بمرور الوقت.
Similarly, you want to make frequent commits with descriptive messages.
وبنفس الطريقة تريد إدخال إيداعات متتالية برسائل وصفية.
This will make it easy to look back at the project and see how it has evolved.
سيمكنك ذلك من الرجوع إلي المشروع بسهولة لترى كيف تطور.
We're not making commits just yet,
لم نقم بإدخال إيداعات حتى الآن،
but start getting used to the idea that you should make
ولكن تعوّد على فكرة أنك يجب أن تقوم
commits often with descriptive commit messages.
بإدخال إيداعات كثيرة برسائل وصفية.
But how often is often,
ولكن كثرة إلى أي مدى،
and how can you know what makes a good commit?
وكيف يمكنك أن تعرف الإيداع الجيد؟
How many files or lines of code should be included in the commit?
ما هو عدد الملفات والسطور التي يجب أن يتضمنها الإيداع؟
One of the best ways to know what makes a good commit is to look at existing commits.
إحدى الطرق الجيدة لمعرفة الإيداع الجيد هي النظر إلى الإيداعات الحالية.
The tools we'll be using to review a repository's history are git log and git show.
الأدوات التي سنستخدمها لمراجعة تاريخ المستودع هي git log و git show.
With git log, you'll be able to display information about the existing commits.
بواسطة git log، ستتمكن من عرض معلومات عن الإيداعات الموجودة.
Git log is extremely powerful and you'll be using it all of the time.
Git log قوي جدًا وستستخدمه طوال الوقت.
The git show command displays info about the given commit.
أما أمر git show فيعرض معلومات عن الإيداع المُدخل.
So, with this one, you provide it the commit ID,
لذلك، مع git show، تقوم بإدخال مُعرف الإيداع،
also known as the SHA,
ويُعرف أيضًا بـ SHA،
and the command displays info about just that one commit.
ويعرض الامر معلومات عن إيداع واحد فقط.
Just two commands, git log and git show.
اثنين فقط من الأوامر، git log و git show.
Seem small, right? But this might actually be the most important lesson in the course.
ألا يبدو الأمر بسيطًا؟ لكن قد يكون هذا أهم درس في الدورة التدريبية حقًا.
Learning how to display a repository's history and reviewing
التعلم كيف يمكنك عرض تاريخ المستودع والمراجعة
specific commits is useful for so many things.
توجد إيداعات معينة مفيدة في كثير من الأشياء.
Are you ready? You're focused?
هل أنت جاهز؟ هل أنت في كامل تركيزك؟
Let's look at the all powerful git log.
دعنا نرى git log القوي.